Register of the Leon Gouré papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Printed Monographs, 1919-1968 (Box 47-51)
  Includes inscriptions and annotations
  - Aronson, Grigorii, Bol'shevistskaia revoliutsiia i men'sheviki. New York, 1955 (Box 47)
  - Bénouville, Guillain de, Le Sacrifice du matin. Paris, undated (Box 47)
  - Blum, Léon, L'Histoire jugera. Montreal, 1943 (Box 47)
  - El Campesino, La Vie et la mort en U.R.S.S., 1939-1949. Paris, 1950 (Box 47)
  - Les Carnets secrets du Comte Ciano. Paris, undated (Box 47)
  - Castro Delgado, Enrique, J'ai perdu la foi Ã Moscou. Paris, 1950 (Box 47)
  - Chernov, Viktor, Rozhdenie revoliutsionnoi Rossii: Fevral'skaia revoliutsiia. Paris, 1934 (Box 47)
  - Documents on the Events Preceding the Outbreak of the War. Berlin,, and New York, (German Foreign Office publication), 1939 1940 (Box 47)
  - Dvinov, Boris L., Ot legal'nosti k podpol'iu, 1921-1922. Stanford, 1968 (Box 48)
  - Dvinov, Boris L., Vlasovskoe dvizhenie v svete dokumentov. New York, 1950 (Box 48)
  - Einsiedel, Heinrich Graf von, Tagebuch der Versuchung. Berlin, 1950 (Box 48)
  - Ferrero, Guglielmo, Pouvoir: Les génies invisibles de la cité. New York, 1942 (Box 48)
  - Frischauer, Paul, Garibaldi. Paris, undated (Box 48)
  - Heroic Leningrad: Documents, Sketches and Stories of Its Siege and Relief. Moscow, 1945 (Box 48)
  - Karov, D., Partizanskoe dvizhenie v SSSR v 1941-1945 gg. Munich, 1954 (Box 48)
  - Kautsky, Karl, Terrorizm' i kommunizm'. Berlin, 1919 (Box 48)
  - Koyré, Alexandre, Introduction Ã la lecture de Platon. New York, 1945 (Box 48)
  - Lenin, V. I., The Paris Commune. New York, 1931 (Box 49)
  - Lenin, V. I., State and Revolution. New York, 1932 (Box 49)
  - Lenin, V. I., Über den historischen Materialismus. Vienna, undated (Box 49)
  - Martov i ego blizkie: Sbornik. New York, 1959 (Box 49)
  - Monnerot, Jules, Sociologie du communisme. Paris, 1949 (Box 49)
  - Nazi-Soviet Relations, 1939-1941: Documents from the Archives of the German Foreign Office. Washington, 1948 (Box 49)
  - Paul-Boncour, J., Entre deux guerres: Souvenirs sur la IIIe République. 2 volumes. Paris, 1945-1946 (Box 49)
  - Paul-Boncour, J., Entre deux guerres: Souvenirs sur la IIIe République. 2 volumes. New York, 1946 (Box 49)
  - Pertinax, Les Fossoyeurs: Défaite militaire de la France, armistice, contre-révolution. 2 volumes. New York, 1943 (Box 50)
  - Protiv techeniia: Sbornik. New York, 1952 (Box 50)
  - Protiv techeniia: Sbornik. New York, 1954 (Box 50)
  - Rossi, A., Les Communistes français pendant la drôle de guerre. Paris, 1951 (Box 50)
  - Rossi, A., Deux ans d'alliance germano-soviétique, Août 1939-Juin 1941. Paris, 1949 (Box 50)
  - Rossi, A., Physiologie du Parti communiste français. Paris, 1948 (Box 50)
  - Rougier, Louis, Les Accords Pétain-Churchill: Histoire d'une mission secrète. Montreal, 1945 (Box 50)
  - Schuman, Frederick L., Soviet Politics: At Home and Abroad. New York (Box 51)
  - Schwarz, Solomon M., The Russian Revolution of 1905: The Workers' Movement and the Formation of Bolshevism and Menshevism. Chicago, 1967 (Box 51)
  - Tsereteli, I. G., Vospominaniia o fevral'skoi revoliutsii. 2 volumes. Paris, 1963 (Box 51)
  - Zweig, Stefan, Magellan. Paris, 1938 (Box 51)
- Audiovisual Material, undated (Box 52-59)
  Photograph, film strips, and slides
  - Photograph of Gouré receiving award, undated (Box 52)
  - Film strips of Soviet civil defense posters and literature, undated (Box 52)
    - Chem opasno bakteriologicheskoe oruzhie, [How biological weapons are dangerous] (Item 183-65)
    - Posle vykhoda iz ochaga porazheniia, [After leaving the center of contamination] (Item 19-183-65)
    - Bor’ba s pozharami, [Fighting fire] (Item 07-3-013)
    - Kak likvidirovat’ khimicheskoe zarazhenie, [How to eliminate chemical contamination (Item 7-3-16)
    - Umei pol’zovat’sia protivogazom, [How to use a gas mask] (Item 07-3-006)
    - Likvidatsiia avarii na kommunal’no-energeticheskikh setiakh, [Eliminating accidents at municipal energy networks] (Item 07-3-20)
    - Spasaia zhivotnykh, [Saving animals] (Item 7-3-019)
    - V bor’be s boleznetvornymi bakteriiami, [Fighting pathogenic bacteria] (Item 7-3-17)
  - Slides of Soviet civil defense posters and literature, undated (Box 52)
  - Slides of Soviet civil defense posters and literature, undated (Box 53-59)
- Oversize File, 1958 (Box 60)
  Oversize publication
  - Sredstva i sposoby protivovozdushnoi oborony naseleniia. Moscow, 1958. (Box 60)
    Soviet civil defense publication